Matthew O'Brien

Brit living and working in Vilnius. Experience in account management and contract handling for public sector customers as part of a leading provider of IT infrastructure business. Great organisational and time management skills and experienced in the use of Microsoft Office, Oracle Netsuite and teamwork tools such as Microsoft Teams and Jira. Currently completing an online web development course with focus on both front end (HTML, CSS & Javascript) and back end (node.js, SQL, MongoDB).



Employment History

Aviation Compliance Specialist at FL Technics, Vilnius

MAY 2023 - JUNE 2023

- Responsible for KYC (Know Your Customer) checks to ensure clients are compliant and not under international sanctions or operating in high risk countries.
- Daily use of CRM and Jira software to perform duties and checks

Partner Alliance Internal Account Manager at Softcat PLC, Manchester, UK

MARCH 2020 - OCTOBER 2022

- Duties consisted of supporting Account Manager in maintenance of customer and partner relationships and creation/editing of contractual elements.
- Heavy emphasis on creation of customer facing quotes and public sector framework contracts in addition to responding to and bidding on tenders. Editing contracts based on drafts provided by both customer and partner. Liaising with legal team to ensure that contracts are compliant and legally sound to protect interests of the company and client.
- Personally heading up customer and partner facing meetings to resolve any issues and maintain working relationships.
- Experience utilising Oracle Netsuite for record keeping and checking payment status.

Contracts Specialist at ANS Group, Manchester, UK

MAY 2018 - MARCH 2020

- Contract specialist working full time at Cloud Services Provider ANS Group.
- Main responsibilities include; liaising with distributors and suppliers to obtain renewal quotes for networking software and device support, processing and placing orders received by customers, working intimately with customers' IT Departments in order to ensure that support contracts are up to date and troubleshooting any issues along with completing any change requests that they may have.

Details

Vilnius, Lithuania +37864803718 matt.ob 95@hotmail.co.uk

Skills

Customer Service

Ability to Work in a Team

Communication Skills

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Advanced Analytical Thinking

Adaptability

Languages

English

References

Dominic Clark from Softcat PLC

dominiccl@softcat.com +44 113 323 5500



- Creating of and sending out of customer invoices once orders are received. Creation and inputting of contract data into internal system.
- Intimate knowledge of both Microsoft Excel and Sage

Education

Bachelor of Arts in English Language & Screen Studies at University of Manchester, Manchester, UK

SEPTEMBER 2013 – JUNE 2016

Graduated with Upper Second Class honours (2:1)

Computing, Music Technology & English Language at Loreto College, Manchester, UK

SEPTEMBER 2011 – JULY 2013

Courses

Web Development at Udemy

JUNE 2023 – AUGUST 2023

Link to repositories: https://github.com/mattyob95

Course covers:

Front End Development

- Advanced HTML Completed
- Intermediate CSS (including use of frameworks such as Bootstrap Completed
- Javascript In progress
- React.js

Back End Development

- Node
- React
- MongoDB
- Web3
- DApps